Fedor Lisin

Junior Data Scientist

Tbilisi, Tbilisi GE

TheoLisin (https://github.com/TheoLisin) @@TedFox (https://t.me/TedFox)

in theo-lisin (https://www.linkedin.com/in/theo-lisin/)

It took me around two years to realise that I like programming in general and data science in particular. Since taking the Yandex classes, well-written, readable code has become my intention. My current focus is creating products that benefit or facilitate the lives of people, not just reviewers.

SKILLS

ML and Data Science

Intermediate

sklearn | PyTorch | statistics | linear algebra

C/C++ Beginner

Python Development

Intermediate

FastAPI | Pydantic | ORM | SQLAlchemy | ML frameworks

Common

VSC | Gitlab | Github | Reviewing |

CI/CD Beginner

Docker | Docker Compose | Github Actions | Gitlab Pipelines

WORK EXPERIENCE

2023 - Current

Python Developer at Supervisely OÜ

Create a new app on the Supervisely platform and provide client tech help.

App for tracking on video of points, polygons, and rectangles using linear interpolation and NN.

2021 - 2022

Junior Data Scientist at OCRV, Russian Railways affiliated company

Developed different models from scratch for tabular data and time series, upgraded the current data infrastructure, supervised the students' self-study pet projects.

- Train delay investigation system: improving data infrastructure, time to create the final dataset was at least cut in half. (Catboost, SQL, ClickHouse)
- EEG motor imaginary classification: examining the primary methods for getting, classifying, and filtering EEG data, as well as developing experimental data collection methods. (ICA, SSP, WPD)
- Recommendation system for ticket sales (students project): aided students in using their repository and fixed django framework issues. (Git, Conda, Django)

PROJECTS

Voice emotion recognition using Wav2Vec

2021 - 2021

https://github.com/TheoLisin/Emotion_Recognition_with_Wav2Vec (https://github.com/TheoLisin/Emotion_Recognition_with_Wav2Vec)

Skills acquired: Wav2Vec | transformers | telegram-api

Speech emotion recognition model based on Wav2Vec with telegam-bot user interface.

- Trained 8-class classifier on RAVDESS dataset using Wav2Vec pre-trained model.
- Developed a Telegram bot to gather more data and test the model on Russian speech.

Monotone Hurwitz numbers in genus zero

2019 - 2020

 $\textbf{Skills acquired:} \ \text{mathematical physics} \ | \ \text{graph theory}$

University-authored bachelor's thesis

EDUCATION

Bachelor Theoretical Physics at St. Petersburg Academic University of RAS

Data Science, MLOps at MADE Data Academy

2022 - 2023

CERTIFICATES

Machine learning | course authored by Stanford University

Coursera, Stanford University

2020-07-25

https://coursera.org/share/fcf17fea90f4868b828c71c2cad3ff7c (https://coursera.org/share/fcf17fea90f4868b828c71c2cad3ff7c)

Artificial Intelligence Technology | 6-month course

Yandex School of data analysis

2021-08-10

LANGUAGES

EnglishIntermediate

Russian
Native Speaker

INTERESTS

Games Airplanes Traveling

Skills acquired: PPL